-嗨  大家  -嗨
- Hey, guys. - Hey.
亲爱的  这周末我有订到
Honey, I got us that room
那个伍德福特饭店
at the Woodford lnn this weekend.
就是在佛蒙特的  我的暗示果然有用
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
你们这周未不能外出啊
You can't go away this weekend.
那天是艾玛生日
It's Emma's birthday.
会有一个派对
We're having a party.
能不能等我们回来再举办呢
Can't you have the party when we get back?
不要啊  那就不是她真正的生日
No. It won't be her real birthday.
如果她就一岁
Gee, if only she were 1
也不知道生日到底是什么就好了
and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
这对我们很重要呢
Come on, you guys, this is really important to us.
很抱歉  我和钱德勒真的
Sorry, but Chandler and l could really
希望一起度个假日
use a weekend away...
我们想沟通沟通  心理上的
...you know, to reconnect, emotionally.
我们从以前就很想做这件事
There's this thing I really want us to do.
我在《马克西姆》杂志看到的
I read about it in Maxim.
你们可以选择其他日子吧
Well, can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
我们非常希望大家都能来...
Yeah, we want everyone to be there.
当然我也抱歉耽误你
As much as I hate to delay your doing
对我妹妹做那些奇怪性事
weird sex stuff to my little sister.
你们听着  这是一件大事呢
And, I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
没有姑姑和姑父陪伴
How can we have her first birthday party
让她怎么度过她的一岁生日
without her aunt and her uncle?
好的  我们会留下来
All right, we'll stay.
完事儿再开车过去
We can just drive up after the party.
好吧  如果派对的事情
Fine. But if we end up
害我们没做杂志上的事情
not doing this Maxim thing because of this party--
那不是不做的理由  好不好
Believe me, that is not why we won't be doing that.
《老友记》  第十季  第4集 艾玛的生日蛋糕
Friends S10E04 The One With The Cake
你知道吗  菲比
You know, Pheebs,
我小的时候过生日...
when I was little, on my birthday...
我爸会在家里
...my daddy would hide a present
每个房间藏礼物
in every room of the house.
然后会给我们"宝藏地图"
And then he would draw a treasure map
叫我们自己找
to help me find them all.
我喜欢这种家庭习俗
I love family traditions like that.
我跟厄休拉小的时候
When Ursula and I were kids,
过生日
on our birthday...
我们的继父会去卖他的血
...our stepdad would sell his blood
来买吃的
to buy us food.
-嗨  大家  -嗨
- Hey, guys. - Hi.
我带了摄像机  来录艾玛的派对
I brought the camera for Emma's video.
喔  好呢
Oh, good!
我们想要录艾玛的派对
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma...
当她十八岁时  再拿给他看
...and we'll give it to her when she's 18.
酷
Oh, cool.
-就像一个"时空胶囊"  -是啊
- Wow, it's like a time capsule. - Yeah.
想象一下  到时她就会用一个现在还未发明的
Oh, just think, she's gonna be watching that video on a TV...
电视机来看这个影带
...that hasn't even been invented yet...
跟现在和她一样还是婴儿的朋友一起看
...with friends who, right now, are just, like, babies.
然后  他们住在一个浮起来的城市
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built...
为了逃避蚂蚁人
...to escape the ant people.
希望是如此
That's the hope.
所以  艾玛起来了吗
So is Emma awake yet?
没有  现在午睡时间
No, it's still naptime.
不过  马上她就醒了
But she'll be up soon.
乔伊在哪里呢
Where's Joey?
我说过了  现在是午睡时间
I said, it's still naptime.
-嗨  乔伊叔叔来了  -嘿
- Hey, there's Uncle Joey. - Hey.
说句话给十八岁生日的艾玛吧
Hey, say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
-十八岁了  -乔伊  不要
- Eighteen, huh? - Joey, no!
怎么啦  怎么啦  是要给她很辣的朋友
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
当她们看到这个  你已经是五十二岁了
When they see this, you'll be 52.
就是我开始想稳定下来的时候呢
And starting to think about settling down.
乔伊  帮我把这个支起来
Joey, will you please set this up for people
这样就可以放艾玛的礼物
to put Emma's presents on?
非常愿意呢
Love to. Yeah.
我们要给她礼物吗
We were supposed to bring presents?
是啊  我写了一首歌给艾玛
Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
我怎么会知道呢
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
这是一个生日派对啊
Joey, it's a birthday party.
是啊  但她仅一岁而已
Yeah, but for a 1-year-old.
有什么意义
What's the point?
那天她对着杯子大笑一个多小时
The other day she laughed for an hour at a cup.
只是一个普通杯子上面有阿母穿的像农夫的图案
Just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it, dressed as a farmer.
阿母站在牛旁边  牛说  "阿母..."
And he's standing next to this cow, and the cow says, "El-moo."
真是好笑的杯子
Man, that's a funny cup.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
生日的女主角呢
Where's the birthday girl?
她还在睡觉呢
Oh, she's still napping.
当然  她昨晚知道要办一个派对
She was probably up all night excited about the party
肯定太兴奋了  睡不着
she knows is happening.
我知道你们很想去佛蒙特
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont,
对你们也是一件大事
and this isn't a big deal to you.
但这对我们也是一件大事  好吗
But it really is to us, okay?
艾玛不会再有第二次的一岁生日
Emma will never have a first birthday again.
好的  你对  我们很抱歉
You're right. We're sorry.
那把艾玛叫醒
Let's wake up Emma
开始派对吧
and get the fun time started!
她昨晚睡不好所以我们不能叫醒她
She didn't sleep well last night, so we can't wake her.
你是不是在跟我开玩笑啊  姓格林的
Are you frigging kidding me, Greene?
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi! - Hey!
很高兴你们来了
I'm so glad you came.
真不敢相信  艾玛已经一岁了
I can't believe Emma's already 1.
我还记得你的一岁生日
I remember your first birthday.
罗斯很嫉妒我们把注意力都放在你身上
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
他很用力地去拉他的蛋蛋
He pulled on his testicles so hard...
我们不得不要带他去看急诊
...we had to take him to the emergency room.
有些关于你爸爸的事情你还不知道
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
盖勒先生和太太
Hey, Mr. And Mrs. Geller.
我帮你放下来吧
Let me help you with that.
-谢谢  -太好了
- Thank you. - Oh, man, this is great, huh?
我们三个又聚在一起
The three of us together again.
你们怎样会更有趣吗
You know what would be fun?
就当做这礼物是我们三个人
If we gave this present
一起送给艾玛的
to Emma from all of us.
你是哪一位啊
Which one are you?
真不敢相信  艾玛还在睡
I can't believe Emma's still asleep.
我知道  怎么办啊
I know. What are we gonna do?
我有计划  一个好计划
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我会把这个盘子
I'm going to ram this platter
很用力的砸到你肋骨上
really hard into your ribs.
那你会痛的哇哇大叫
You're gonna scream out,
这样会吵醒她
and that'll wake her up.
我不会和这种莫妮卡去佛蒙特的
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
嗨  菲比  你知道吗
Hey, Pheebs? You know what?
即然你写了歌给艾玛
I was thinking since you wrote a song...
那我也可以用我的才能给艾玛做些事
...maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
所以  你要去泡她
So you're gonna hit on her?
不是  不是啦  我的才能是表演啊
No, no, no. My talents as an actor.
我可以  可以...
You know, I could, like, maybe....
给她边读本书边演出来
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
或是  你可以把一个叉子叉在苹果上
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
我想艾玛会喜欢的
Hey, I think Emma might like it.
艾玛会喜欢什么
Oh, Emma might like what?
-我的礼物  -你要给他什么
- My present. - What did you get her?
实际上  我们正准备一个表演
We prepared performances.
分开的的表演呢
Separate performances.
但都是真的
But equally real.
听起来好好玩了
That sounds like fun.
你知道吗  因为大家很不耐烦
People are getting a little antsy
要等艾玛起来
waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
所以  你们可以现在表演一个吗
So would you mind performing them once now?
-当然可以  -好...好  那好吧
- Sure, yeah! - Okay.
大家听着  我们开始吧
Okay. All right. Everybody, let's get this party started.
乔伊和菲比要表演给大家看呢
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
太好了
Oh, great.
那你会不会觉丢脸
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed
上去没东西演
having nothing prepared?
我每个礼拜经历这样的事情
I do it every week
三台摄像机对着我
with three cameras pointed at me
整个剧组在等
and a whole crew waiting.
那乔伊你要表演什么呢
So, Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
我会生动地演读一本艾玛的书
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
好耶  哪一本
Oh, okay. Which one?
哇  他的收藏的其中一个
Well, it's one of her favorites.
《从暴风雨中脱险:对抗产后的抑郁症》
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
《爱你永远》
Love You Forever.
《爱你永远》作者:罗柏·曼
"Love You Forever, by Robert Munsch.
萤火虫出版社出版
Published by Firefly Books. Printed...
在墨西哥印刷...
...in Mexico.
一个母亲抱起她的婴儿
A mother held her new baby
慢慢的  往前摇  往后摇
and very slowly rocked him...
往前摇  往后摇...
...back and forth,
back and forth, back and forth.
当母亲抱着时  她唱了
And while she held him, she sang,
我会永远爱你
I'll love you forever.
我会一直喜欢你
I'll like you for always.
只要我还活着
As long as I'm living...
我的孩子
...my baby you'll be.
当他抱着她时  他唱了
"And while he rocked her, he sang:
我会永远爱你
I'll love you forever.
我会一直喜欢你
I'll like you for always.
只要我还活着
As long as I'm living...
我的孩子
...my baby you'll be.
哇
Oh, wow!
真的太棒了
That was amazing.
真的非常感谢你的礼物
Thank you so much for that gift.
我今天没有这个心理准备
I was not ready for this today.
-太棒了  太棒了  -菲比  抱歉
- Amazing. Amazing. - Phoebe, I'm sorry.
菲比也要表演给大家看
Phoebe has prepared something as well.
没错
That's right.
我准备了一首歌给艾玛
I prepared a song for Emma,
这首歌让我俩的心相连
from my heart to hers.
没有比音乐更好的礼物了
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
艾玛  你的名字给我一个困境
Emma Your name poses a dilemma
和你名字押韵的字极少
'Cause not much else rhymes with "Emma"
也许仅有演员理查德·克里纳
Maybe the actor Richard Crenna
他曾出演《蓝波》中的长官
He played the commanding officer in Rambo
生日快乐  艾玛
Happy birthday, Emma
就这样
Is that it?
不  当然不是  还有
No, of course not.
其他...  我也要读一本书给他
No, I've also, you know, prepared a reading.
《性爱和单身母亲》
"Sex and the Single Mother."
-找到你的G点  -不要啊
- "Finding your G-spot." - Oh, no, no, no!
嗨  艾玛  祝你十八岁生日快乐
Hello, Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
如果从现在算起  还有十七年之久呢
Right now, that seems so far away, 17 years.
到时候你已经长大了
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then,
而到时候我们...
and we'll be....
你爷爷和我可能都不在了
Well, your grandfather and l might not be here.
没错  这信息可能是从阴间
That's true. This message could be coming to you...
传给你的  艾玛
...from beyond the grave, Emma.
毕竟我父母亲很年轻就过世了
After all, my parents died very young.
我的胆固醇还过高呢
And my cholesterol's off the charts.
艾玛  请记住
Remember, Emma,
女生也会死于心脏病
heart disease kills women too.
好了  停  这样就够了
Okay, cut! Great. Great. That was just....
哦  好的
Oh, good.
罗斯  别忘了要拍蛋糕
Ross, don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
-盒子在冰箱里  -好的  没问题
- It's in a box in the fridge. - Okay, sure.
你会喜欢这蛋糕
You're gonna love this cake.
我从新泽西州的面包店买来的
I got it from a bakery in New Jersey,
加理诺面包店
Carino's.
他们有全世界最好吃的奶油
Oh, my God, that place has the creamiest frosting!
我小时候喜欢搭便车去那里
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
无论如何
Well, anyway,
他们可以做很多新颖的蛋糕
they make these great novelty cakes...
也很多种造型
...in all different shapes.
如果你自己准备照片
And if you give them a photo,
他们还会放到蛋糕上
they'll copy it in icing.
那你一定放艾玛的照片喽
Did you do a picture of Emma?
当然  在一个兔子形的蛋糕
Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
瑞秋
Rach?
这家店是不是刚好
Does this bakery by any chance also bake...
也卖色情蛋糕
...erotic cakes?
或许给单身派对使用
Say, for bachelorette parties?
你在讲什么啊  喔  我的天啊
Ross, what are you talking--? Oh, my God!
他们还把我女儿的脸放在"小弟弟"上
They put my baby's face on a penis!
这才像派对嘛
Now it's a party!
这一点都不好笑
Wait, you guys, this isn't funny.
如果我想让这蛋糕成为一场灾难
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster,
我可以自己做啊
I would have baked it myself!
我还是觉得它很好吃啊
Is it okay
这样没问题吧
that I still think it looks delicious?
杰克  你看看
Jack, look at this.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking, Judy.
其相似程度非常惊人
The resemblance is uncanny.
我也差点再度拉我的蛋蛋
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
不  不是  这不是我要订的
No, no, this is not what I ordered, okay?
我特地去新泽西
I went all the way to New Jersey
只为了我女儿有完美的生日蛋糕
so that I could have the perfect cake...
还有  我需要兔子蛋糕  现在
...for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
如果要快点的话
Ask them if it would be faster
我们可以从"小弟弟"上取出孩子的照片
if we cut the baby's face off the penis...
再贴到兔子蛋糕上
...so we could put it on the bunny.
这句话太奇怪了
That is a weird sentence.
相信我  我会把蛋糕换回去
Oh, believe you me, I am going to bring this cake back.
甚至我不想有这种蛋糕放在我家
I don't even want it in my home.
乔伊  不要碰
Joey. Don't touch it!
我很疑惑啊
I'm so confused!
是的  我还是要我女儿照片
Yes, I still want my daughter's picture,
但是在兔子形状的蛋糕上
but on a bunny cake!
黄色蛋糕  有巧克力霜和坚果（nuts:坚果  也指男性睾丸）
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
公平来讲  你说的东西这上面的确有
To be fair, this one does have nuts.
莫妮卡  你真好啊  把车借给瑞秋
Mon, it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car...
让她可以去换蛋糕
...so she could get the cake.
谢谢她一直揪我头发
It was nice of her to pull my hair...
直到我把钥匙丢了
...till I dropped the key.
既然闲着
Well, while we're waiting,
你们就先录一段
you could tape your message to Emma...
给艾玛的十八岁生日的祝福  好不好
...for her 18th birthday, huh? Okay?
艾玛  现在是2020年
Hi, Emma. It's the year 2020.
你还在享受你的午觉吗
Are you still enjoying your nap?
我们是莫妮卡姑姑和钱德勒姑父
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler, by the way.
你可能不认识我们
You may not recognize us...
因为我们已经十七年
...because we haven't spoken
没有和你父母亲讲话了
to your parents in 17 years.
我们曾经结过婚
We used to be married.
但我们搞砸了我们的一个周末
But then we missed a weekend away together,
造成我们分开
and things kind of unraveled...
就是因为你
...because of you.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
罗斯  瑞秋答应过
Ross, Rachel promised
派对这时候会完
it would be over by now.
我们如果要去佛蒙特
We seriously have to go
现在该出发了
if we want to get to Vermont.
我打电话问过他们了
I called them,
最后一班火车在半小时后
the last train leaves in a half-hour.
我有要按摩的客户
And I have a massage client soon.
大家忍耐一下
You guys, just, please, a little bit longer.
我保证
I promise,
瑞秋随时会带蛋糕回来
Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
莫妮卡  记得该店的奶油味道吗
Monica, remember the frosting, huh?
好吧  我再等五分钟
All right, five more minutes.
喂
Hello?
不是吧  发生什么事
Oh, no, what happened?
好的  好的  你在哪里
Okay, okay, where are you?
我马上过去
Okay, I'll be right there.
是不是艾玛
Was that Emma?
她起来了吗
Is she up?
瑞秋因超速被警察拦下来
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
他忘了带驾照
She forgot her license.
我得送过去
I have to bring it to her.
如果你要走那我也得走
If you're leaving, I'm definitely going.
如果有人要走那就是我们
Wait, if anybody gets to go, it's us!
我们是抱怨最久的
We've been complaining the longest!
等等  你们不能走
No, wait, you guys. No, you can't leave.
蛋糕的事已让瑞秋很烦
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
如果回来时发现大家不在
How do you think she'll feel
那她会怎么想
when she comes back and you're gone?
我不知道  你礼拜一才会告诉我们
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
乔伊  你负责这里
Joey, you're in charge, okay?
谁也不许走
You make sure nobody leaves.
了解
Got it!
嘿嘿嘿  你要去哪
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
去洗手间啊
To the bathroom.
大家怎么舒服怎么来
Well, the rest of you get comfortable,
因为我们还要待在这...
because we are gonna be here for a--
等等  洗手间里有个窗户...
Wait, there's a window in there.
不要让他逃走
No! He's not getting away that easy!
你们干什么啊
What are you doing?
快滚出去啊
Get the hell out of here!
那个"小弟弟"上没有艾玛的照片
Well, that one did not have Emma's face on it.
-是  没有  -对
- No, it did not. - No.
已经很晚了  我们真的要走了
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
杰克不能在晚上开车了
Jack can't drive at night anymore.
他不能保持在自己的车道里
He has trouble staying in his lane.
去年冬天我开车经过教堂的草地
Last winter I went up on a church lawn
然后撞上马的食槽
and drove right through a manger scene.
报纸误以为那是报复性犯罪
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
-无论如何  很高兴可以见到你们  -好的
- Anyway, it was lovely seeing you. - Okay.
-再见  -晚安
- Bye. Bye, dear. - Nighty-night.
-晚安  -再见.
- Nighty-night. - Bye.
乔伊  你怎么可以让他们走
How could you just let them leave?
嘿嘿嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
我不会和杰克过不去的
I'm not gonna mess with Jack.
他是一个能为国家而战的伟人
He's a great man. He fought for our country.
他才没有呢
No, he didn't.
他装成贵格会教徒
He pretended to be a Quaker
才可以逃离韩国
to get out of Korea.
够了  他是最后一个退出的
Well, that's it. He's the last one to go.
我把门锁上了
I'm locking you guys in.
你知道那个锁是
You do know I can just turn them
可以从这里面打开的
the other way around, right?
我忘了你以前住过这里
Oh, I forgot you used to live here.
-喂  -乔伊  我是埃斯特尔
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
-嗨  -你今天的试镜如何
- Hey. - So how'd your audition go today?
什么试镜
What audition?
上礼拜我和你是过的啊
The one I told you about last week.
什么  你根本没有说过任何试镜
What? You never said anything about an audition.
那我重新说
Let me start over.
我刚接到一个试镜通知
I just got a call about an audition.
你现在去还来得及
I think you can still make it.
就在紫苑戏院
It's down at the Astor Theater,
还要自己带独白
and you need to have a monologue prepared.
独白  我没有...
A monologue? I don't have a--
有了...
I got it.
那我要走了
So I'm gonna take off.
什么
What?
不  等等  你不能走
No, wait! You don't get to leave.
我有按摩客户会随时到我家门外呢
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
房间的钱我们已经付了
And we paid for a room
我们早该在里面
that we're supposed to be in right now!
好好
Well, okay, now...
只要有一个人照顾艾玛就行了
...only one of us has to stay with Emma.
因我刚发现这点所以我可以走了
Okay, and as the person who realized that, I get to go.
不行...
No...
那我们想一个较公平的方法来决定谁要留下来
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
有了
Oh, I got it.
大家选择一到十的数字
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to 10, all right?
谁选到最大的数字可以先走
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
好喔  我选"十"
Okay, 10.
莫妮卡选"十"  那我选"九"
Okay, Monica picks 10. I call nine.
还有其他的吗
Anyone else?
-大家来抽签吧  -好
- No, let's just draw straws. - Okay.
或是可以扔硬币  答对次数...
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer--
-拜托你  不要讲话了  -好  .
- I'm begging you to stop. - Right.
这样好啦  我们从艾玛的
Okay, how about this?
生日礼物选一个发条玩具
We got wind-up toys for Emma.
拿来赛跑
We can make them race,
哪个跑最后的  就要留下来
and whoever comes in last stays.
好吧  就这样
Yeah, let's do that!
这好像比我们要
That sounds more fun than the thing
在佛蒙特做的事情好玩
we were gonna do in Vermont!
好  各位  开始选玩具吧
Okay, everybody, pick your toys!
我要用那个海豚
Okay. I want the dolphin!
-那是一只熊  -我太兴奋了
- That's a bear! - I'm too excited!
菲比  你用这只熊
Phoebe, you get the bear.
乔伊  你用机器人
Joey, you get the robot.
哦  好的
Oh, yeah.
钱德勒就用这只狗吧
And Chandler and I get the dog.
比赛就  从这里到这里
And the race is going to go from here to here.
谁最后一名的  留下来
Now, the one who comes in last stays!
各位先生及女士
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
卷好你的发条
wind your toys.
准备了吗  预备  开始
Okay. On your mark, get set, go!
快  快
Go! Go!
不要停  机器人
Come on, robot!
你叫什么呢
What are you barking at?
那个动作有什么用
Well, how is that gonna help?
我买的你
I bought you!
我竟忘了你只会这个动作
How did I forget that that's all you do?
好样的  机器人
Way to go, robot!
干得好  熊熊
Good job, Alan.
真的一个好比赛
Hey, good race, you guys.
是啊  那就再见喽
Yeah, see you later.
不  不  你们等一下
No. No, no. Wait.
我们没有输呢
We didn't lose.
规则是说
The rules clearly stated that
最后跑到终点才是输家
the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
那我们的狗
Well, our dog never crossed
没有跑到终点  所以...
the finish line. So technically--
他们已经走了
They left.
根本没时间去面包店
There isn't time to go to the bakery.
所以我们现在回家了
We're gonna come home.
大家已经走了
Everybody left?
好吧  告诉艾玛
All right. Well, just tell Emma
我们会尽快回家  再见
that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
-瑞秋  -喔  天啊  抱歉
- Rachel! - Oh, God, sorry!
真不敢相信  他们给了你一个罚单
I can't believe they gave you a ticket.
你是多好的驾驶员
You're such a good driver.
-艾玛醒了  -是喔
- Emma's awake. - Yeah?
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
在她的一岁生日
This is her first birthday,
她醒来时我们不在
she's awake, we're not even there.
大家也都走了
Everybody left.
还加上这个烂蛋糕
We still have this stupid obscene cake.
也许我可以弄好这蛋糕
Hey, maybe I can fix that.
试试看  改成别的形状嘛
You know, try to turn it into something else.
已经无所谓了
Oh, don't even bother.
我们已经毁了她的第一个生日
We've already ruined her first birthday.
你不知道
And do you know
这些早期的经验对她有多重要吗
how important these early experiences are,
罗斯  非常重要
Ross? Very!
你给我的那本书背面是这么说的
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
瑞秋  她不会记得这些
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
也许吧
I guess.
我本来想像着
Oh, I just had such an idea
今天会是怎样的一天
of what this day would be like, you know?
艾玛在笑
Emma laughing...
大家围绕着蛋糕
...and everybody gathered around her cake,
唱"生日快乐"
singing "Happy Birthday."
然后我们...
And then we would all--
嘿  不要挡老娘的路
Hey, get out of the road,
白痴新手
you stupid student driver!
他们总要学这点
They have to learn.
-嘿  -什么
- Hey. - What?
这样不错嘛
This is not bad.
天啊  你把它变成小兔子了
Oh, my God. Look, you made it into a bunny.
你怎么弄的
How did you do that?
我把这俩东西改成脸颊
Well, I just made these two things cheeks.
把这东西分成两份  变成耳朵
And then I split this to make ears.
我非常感动呢
Well, I am very impressed.
有些人会唱歌  有些人会跳舞
Some can sing, some can dance.
我显然的可以
I, apparently, can turn phallic cakes
把"小弟弟"改成兔子蛋糕
into woodland creatures.
还有另外一种方法来整理玩具
Now, another way to organize your stuffed animals
就是按照大小
is by size.
对不起  这是给艾玛玩的游戏
I'm sorry, is this a game
还是给莫妮卡
for Emma or for Monica?
游戏
Game?
艾玛 你知道今天是你生日吗
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today?
你一岁了
You're 1.
就是一岁  这么小
One year old. That's little.
好丫头
That's my girl.
这就是你的年龄
That's how old you are.
是我教她的吗
Did I teach her that?
我传授智慧给她
Did I just impart wisdom?
我也想要有一个
I want one.
我也是
Me too.
这里又没人
There's no one around.
干脆我们把这个带走
Why don't we just take this one?
-然后跑去加拿大  -我在开玩笑
- And head to Canada. - I was kidding.
我可没有呢  快点出发吧
I wasn't. Let's get going.
嘿  罗斯和瑞秋回来了吗
Hey, are Ross and Rachel back?
还没有呢
No, not yet.
喔  好耶  我没错过派对嘛
Oh, good, I didn't miss the party.
那你的按摩客户呢
What about your massage client?
我觉得很内疚如果错过这派对
I just felt so bad missing this.
所以我给他吃了点东西
So I just slipped him a little something, you know.
只要我五或六个小时后
As long as I'm back in five or six hours,
能回去就行
it'll be all right.
好
Okay.
如果罗斯和瑞秋问起我
If Ross and Rachel ask,
就说我一直待在这里  一直
I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
我一直待在这里的
I've been here the whole time.
乔伊  我们刚看到你进来
Joey, we just saw you come in.
而且你跑上来时  在楼梯有超过我们
You ran past us on the stairs.
我不管你有没有离开
I don't care that you left.
我很高兴你们现在在这里
I'm just glad that you're here.
谢谢大家
Thanks, you guys.
大家过来
Hey, guys, come on.
你们应该看看艾玛刚做了什么
You gotta see what Emma just did.
-什么  -艾玛  你几岁
- What? - Emma, how old are you?
你今天几岁
How old are you today?
对了  艾玛就是那么一岁
Emma, that's right. You're that many.
天啊  我们女儿是一个天才
Oh, my God, our daughter's a genius.
-这表示...  -不要有科学的说教了
- This means-- - No! No science camp!
真是的  我把蜡烛放到蛋糕上
Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.
艾玛  看看你的娃娃
Oh, and, Emma, look at your stuffed animals
排得如此整齐
lined up so neatly.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了  来了
Okay, here we go.
这是艾玛第一个生日蛋糕
Emma's first birthday cake.
快吹啊  吹灭蜡烛
Go ahead, Emma, blow out the candle.
快  艾玛  你能做到的
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
怎么啦  你还好吧
What's wrong? Are you okay?
喔  没事
Oh, yeah, nothing.
这是快乐的眼泪
These are happy tears.
这就是我想要的
This is just what I wanted.
蛋糕已变成兔子形状的
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
我怎么啦
What is wrong with me?
为什么我觉得"小弟弟"的形状时看来比较好吃
It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
-好  准备了吗  -是的
- Okay, you ready? - Yeah.
-那  开始录了  -好
- And record. - Okay.
嗨  艾玛
Hi, Emma.
你的生日刚结束了  而且...
Well, your first birthday is over, and--
快啊  快啊
Go! Go! Come on!
快啊  快点
熊熊  快跑啊  你这只笨熊
Go! Go, Alan! Run, you hairy bastard!